Victor A. Lora

(201) 289-1355 ♦ victor@victorlora.net ♦ victorlora.net ♦ github.com/victorlora ♦ /in/victorlora95

An upcoming graduate offering a strong academic background in Computer Science and Mathematics combined with excellent internship experience as a Software Developer and NOC Engineer. Strong skills in a range of computer systems, languages, tools and testing methodologies. Successful in both team and self-directed settings. Multi-lingual speaking English, Italian and Spanish. Academic career distinguished by attaining Dean's List every semester and a 3.8/4.0 GPA.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Muhlenberg College, Allentown, PA 2017

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures & Algorithms, Programming Languages, Databases, Software Engineering,

Computer Organization

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Software Development
- Database Administration
- Debugging
- Object Oriented Languages
- Algorithms
- Leadership
- Communication
- Technical Support

- Problem Resolution
- Customer Relationships
- Office Management
- SLA Achievement

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End Coding: HTML5; CSS; JavaScript

Back-End Coding: Java; Python; SQL; PHP; Swift; C++;

Tools & Frameworks: Git; Linux; MySQL; OSX; Postgres; Redmine; Smart GWT; Spring

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SAUCON TECHNOLOGIES, Bethlehem, PA, Software Developer Intern

2015-Present

- Develop a flexible vehicle maintenance system allowing customers to track vehicle maintenance cycles, work orders, inventory, warranties, budgets and more.
- Create, update, debug, and expand dynamic web portal modules and applications based on customer needs and specifications adhering to monthly release cycle.
- Developed a camera tamper detection algorithm using the OpenCV library.

NU-AGE MANAGED SERVICES, Pearl River, NY, NOC Engineer Intern

2014-2015

- Effectively resolved functional and technical issues by troubleshooting and diagnosing hardware, software and network issues on-site, over the phone, and by email.
- Installed and performed repairs to hardware, software and peripheral equipment, following design and installation specifications.
- Documented tickets/resolutions as well as system configurations and technical procedures.

AWARDS & HONORS

Presidential Merit Scholarship, 2013 - Present
The Dr. Anthony J. Marino Jr. Award in Computing Science, 2016
Third Place - PACISE Programming Competition, 2016

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Emerging Leaders Program Member/Mentor, inducted 2013
Cardinal Key Society Member, inducted 2013
Judicial Panel Member, inducted 2014
Peer Tutor, 2015 - Present